[
    {
        "question": "A media company is evaluating the possibility of moving its IT infrastructure to the AWS Cloud. The company needs at least 10 TB of storage with the maximum possible I/O performance for processing certain files which are mostly large videos. The company also needs close to 450 TB of very durable storage for storing media content and almost double of it, i.e. 900 TB for archival of legacy data. As a Solutions Architect, which set of services will you recommend to meet these requirements?",
        "choice1": "Amazon S3 standard storage for maximum performance, Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering for intelligent, durable storage, and Amazon S3 Glacier Deep Archive for archival storage",
        "choice2": "Amazon EBS for maximum performance, Amazon S3 for durable data storage, and Amazon S3 Glacier for archival storage",
        "choice3": "Amazon EC2 instance store for maximum performance, Amazon S3 for durable data storage, and Amazon S3 Glacier for archival storage",
        "choice4": "Amazon EC2 instance store for maximum performance, AWS Storage Gateway for on-premises durable data access and Amazon S3 Glacier Deep Archive for archival storage",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A CRM application is facing user experience issues with users reporting frequent sign-in requests from the application. The application is currently hosted on multiple EC2 instances behind an Application Load Balancer. The engineering team has identified the root cause as unhealthy servers causing session data to be lost. The team would like to implement a distributed in-memory cache-based session management solution. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions would you recommend?",
        "choice1": "Use RDS for distributed in-memory cache-based session management",
        "choice2": "Use DynamoDB for distributed in-memory cache-based session management",
        "choice3": "Use Application Load Balancer sticky sessions",
        "choice4": "Use Elasticache for distributed cache-based session management",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A medium-sized business has a taxi dispatch application deployed on an EC2 instance. Because of an unknown bug, the application causes the instance to freeze regularly. Then, the instance has to be manually restarted via the AWS management console. Which of the following is the MOST cost-optimal and resource-efficient way to implement an automated solution until a permanent fix is delivered by the development team?",
        "choice1": "Setup a CloudWatch alarm to monitor the health status of the instance. In case of an Instance Health Check failure, CloudWatch Alarm can publish to an SNS event which can then trigger a lambda function. The lambda function can use AWS EC2 API to reboot the instance",
        "choice2": "Setup a CloudWatch alarm to monitor the health status of the instance. In case of an Instance Health Check failure, an EC2 Reboot CloudWatch Alarm Action can be used to reboot the instance",
        "choice3": "Use CloudWatch events to trigger a Lambda function to check the instance status every 5 minutes. In the case of Instance Health Check failure, the lambda function can use AWS EC2 API to reboot the instance",
        "choice4": "Use CloudWatch events to trigger a Lambda function to reboot the instance status every 5 minutes",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company hires experienced specialists to analyze the customer service calls attended by its call center representatives. Now, the company wants to move to AWS Cloud and is looking at an automated solution to analyze customer service calls for sentiment analysis and security. As a Solutions Architect, which of the following solutions would you recommend?",
        "choice1": "Use Kinesis Data Streams to read the audio files and machine learning (ML) algorithms to convert the audio files into text and run customer sentiment analysis",
        "choice2": "Use Amazon Transcribe to convert audio files to text and Amazon Athena to understand the underlying customer sentiments",
        "choice3": "Use Kinesis Data Streams to read the audio files and Amazon Alexa to convert them into text. Kinesis Data Analytics can be used to analyze these files and Amazon Quicksight can be used to visualize and display the output",
        "choice4": "Use Amazon Transcribe to convert audio files to text and Amazon Quicksight to run analysis on these text files to understand the underlying patterns. Visualize and display them onto user Dashboards for human analysis",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The Development team at an e-commerce company is working on securing their databases. Which of the following AWS database engines can be configured with IAM Database Authentication? (Select two)",
        "choice1": "RDS Oracle",
        "choice2": "RDS MySQL",
        "choice3": "RDS Maria DB",
        "choice4": "RDS Sequel Server",
        "choice5": "RDS PostGreSQL",
        "answer": "2,5",
        "multi": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A global media company uses a fleet of EC2 instances (behind an Application Load Balancer) to power its video streaming application. To improve the performance of the application, the engineering team has also created a CloudFront distribution with the Application Load Balancer as the custom origin. The security team at the company has noticed a spike in the number and types of SQL injection and cross-site scripting attack vectors on the application. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions would you recommend as the MOST effective in countering these malicious attacks?",
        "choice1": "Use Route 53 with CloudFront distribution",
        "choice2": "Use Security Hub with CloudFront distribution",
        "choice3": "Use Web Application Firewall (WAF) with CloudFront distribution",
        "choice4": "Use AWS Firewall Manager with CloudFront distribution",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company wants to store business-critical data on EBS volumes which provide persistent storage independent of EC2 instances. During a test run, the development team found that on terminating an EC2 instance, the attached EBS volume was also lost, which was contrary to their assumptions. As a solutions architect, could you explain this issue?",
        "choice1": "The EBS volume was configured as the root volume of the Amazon EC2 instance. On termination of the instance, the default behavior is to also terminate the attached root volume",
        "choice2": "The EBS volumes were not backed up on Amazon S3 storage, resulting in the loss of volume",
        "choice3": "The EBS volumes were not backed up on EFS file system storage, resulting in the loss of volume",
        "choice4": "On termination of an EC2 instance, all the attached EBS volumes are always terminated",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The infrastructure team at a company maintains 5 different VPCs (let's call these VPCs A, B, C, D, E) for resource isolation. Due to the changed organizational structure, the team wants to interconnect all VPCs together. To facilitate this, the team has set up VPC peering connections between VPC A and all other VPCs in a hub and spoke model with VPC A at the center. However, the team has still failed to establish connectivity between all VPCs. As a solutions architect, which of the following would you recommend as the MOST resource-efficient and scalable solution?",
        "choice1": "Use an internet gateway to interconnect the VPCs",
        "choice2": "Use a VPC endpoint to interconnect the VPCs",
        "choice3": "Use a transit gateway to interconnect the VPCs",
        "choice4": "Establish VPC peering connections between all VPCs",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A solutions architect has been tasked to design a low-latency solution for a static, single-page application, accessed by users through a custom domain name. The solution must be serverless, provide in-transit data encryption and needs to be cost-effective. Which AWS services can be combined to build the simplest possible solution for the company's requirement?",
        "choice1": "Host the application on Amazon EC2 instance with instance store volume for high performance and low latency access to users",
        "choice2": "Host the application on AWS Fargate and front it with an Elastic Load Balancer for an improved performance",
        "choice3": "Configure Amazon S3 to store the static data and use AWS Fargate for hosting the application",
        "choice4": "Use Amazon S3 to host the static website and Amazon CloudFront to distribute the content for low latency access",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A multi-national company is looking at optimizing their AWS resources across various countries and regions. They want to understand the best practices on cost optimization, performance, and security for their system architecture spanning across multiple business units. Which AWS service is the best fit for their requirements?",
        "choice1": "AWS Config",
        "choice2": "AWS Trusted Advisor",
        "choice3": "AWS Management Console",
        "choice4": "AWS Systems Manager",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company hosts a Network File System on its on-premises data center but it is now looking to adopt a hybrid cloud strategy to connect the on-premise applications to an AWS NFS that is backed by Amazon S3. Which service do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "File Gateway",
        "choice2": "Volume Gateway",
        "choice3": "Tape Gateway",
        "choice4": "Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS)",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A junior developer is learning to build websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. He has created a static website and then deployed it on Amazon S3. Now he can't seem to figure out the endpoint for his super cool website. As a solutions architect, can you help him figure out the allowed formats for the Amazon S3 website endpoints? (Select two)",
        "choice1": "http://s3-website-Region.bucket-name.amazonaws.com",
        "choice2": "http://s3-website.Region.bucket-name.amazonaws.com",
        "choice3": "http://bucket-name.s3-website.Region.amazonaws.com",
        "choice4": "http://bucket-name.Region.s3-website.amazonaws.com",
        "choice5": "http://bucket-name.s3-website-Region.amazonaws.com",
        "answer": "3,5",
        "multi": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A big data analytics company is using Kinesis Data Streams (KDS) to process IoT data from the field devices of an agricultural sciences company. Multiple consumer applications are using the incoming data streams and the engineers have noticed a performance lag for the data delivery speed between producers and consumers of the data streams. As a solutions architect, which of the following would you recommend for improving the performance for the given use-case?",
        "choice1": "Swap out Kinesis Data Streams with Kinesis Data Firehose",
        "choice2": "Swap out Kinesis Data Streams with SQS Standard queues",
        "choice3": "Use Enhanced Fanout feature of Kinesis Data Streams",
        "choice4": "Swap out Kinesis Data Streams with SQS FIFO queues",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Computer vision researchers at a university are trying to optimize the I/O bound processes for a proprietary algorithm running on EC2 instances. The ideal storage would facilitate high-performance IOPS when doing file processing in a temporary storage space before uploading the results back into Amazon S3. As a solutions architect, which of the following AWS storage options would you recommend as the MOST performant as well as cost-optimal?",
        "choice1": "Use EC2 instances with EBS General Purpose SSD (gp2) as the storage option",
        "choice2": "Use EC2 instances with Instance Store as the storage type",
        "choice3": "Use EC2 instances with EBS Provisioned IOPS SSD (io1) as the storage option",
        "choice4": "Use EC2 instances with EBS Throughput Optimized HDD (st1) as the storage option",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "As a Solutions Architect, you have been hired to work with the engineering team at a company to create a REST API using the serverless architecture. Which of the following solutions will you recommend to move the company to the serverless architecture?",
        "choice1": "API Gateway exposing Lambda Functionality",
        "choice2": "Fargate with Lambda at the front",
        "choice3": "Public-facing Application Load Balancer with ECS on Amazon EC2",
        "choice4": "Route 53 with EC2 as backend",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You are a cloud architect at an IT company. The company has multiple enterprise customers that manage their own mobile apps that capture and send data to Amazon Kinesis Data Streams. They have been getting a ProvisionedThroughputExceededException exception. You have been contacted to help and upon analysis, you notice that messages are being sent one by one at a high rate. Which of the following options will help with the exception while keeping costs at a minimum?",
        "choice1": "Use Exponential Backoff",
        "choice2": "Increase the number of shards",
        "choice3": "Use batch messages",
        "choice4": "Decrease the Stream retention duration",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Your company is building a music sharing platform on which users can upload the songs of their choice. As a solutions architect for the platform, you have designed an architecture that will leverage a Network Load Balancer linked to an Auto Scaling Group across multiple availability zones. You are currently running with 100 Amazon EC2 instances with an Auto Scaling Group that needs to be able to share the storage layer for the music files. Which technology do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "EBS volumes mounted in RAID 1",
        "choice2": "EBS volumes mounted in RAID 0",
        "choice3": "Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS)",
        "choice4": "Instance Store",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The data engineering team at an e-commerce company has set up a workflow to ingest the clickstream data into the raw zone of the S3 data lake. The team wants to run some SQL based data sanity checks on the raw zone of the data lake. What AWS services would you recommend for this use-case such that the solution is cost-effective and easy to maintain?",
        "choice1": "Load the incremental raw zone data into Redshift on an hourly basis and run the SQL based sanity checks",
        "choice2": "Load the incremental raw zone data into an EMR based Spark Cluster on an hourly basis and use SparkSQL to run the SQL based sanity checks",
        "choice3": "Use Athena to run SQL based analytics against S3 data",
        "choice4": "Load the incremental raw zone data into RDS on an hourly basis and run the SQL based sanity checks",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The data science team at a mobility company wants to analyze real-time location data of rides. The company is using Kinesis Data Firehose for delivering the location-specific streaming data into targets for downstream analytics. Which of the following targets are NOT supported by Kinesis Data Firehose?",
        "choice1": "Amazon S3",
        "choice2": "Amazon EMR",
        "choice3": "Amazon RedShift",
        "choice4": "Amazon Elasticsearch",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A developer in your team has set up a classic 3 tier architecture composed of an Application Load Balancer, an Auto Scaling group managing a fleet of EC2 instances, and an Aurora database. As a Solutions Architect, you would like to adhere to the security pillar of the well-architected framework. How do you configure the security group of the Aurora database to only allow traffic coming from the EC2 instances?",
        "choice1": "Add a rule authorizing the Aurora security group",
        "choice2": "Add a rule authorizing the ASG's subnets CIDR",
        "choice3": "Add a rule authorizing the ELB security group",
        "choice4": "Add a rule authorizing the EC2 security group",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Reporters at a news agency upload/download video files (about 500MB each) to/from an S3 bucket as part of their daily work. As the agency has started offices in remote locations, it has resulted in poor latency for uploading and accessing data to/from S3. The agency wants to continue using S3 but wants to improve the performance. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions do you propose to address this issue? (Select two)",
        "choice1": "Spin up EC2 instances in each region where the agency has a remote office. Create a daily job to transfer S3 data into EBS volumes attached to the EC2 instances",
        "choice2": "Use Amazon CloudFront distribution with origin as the S3 bucket. This would speed up uploads as well as downloads for the video files",
        "choice3": "Move S3 data into EFS file system created in a US region, connect to EFS file system from EC2 instances in other AWS regions using an inter-region VPC peering connection",
        "choice4": "Enable Amazon S3 Transfer Acceleration for the S3 bucket. This would speed up uploads as well as downloads for the video files",
        "choice5": "Create new S3 buckets in every region where the agency has a remote office, so that each office can maintain its storage for the media assets",
        "answer": "2,4",
        "multi": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A pharmaceutical company is considering moving to AWS Cloud to accelerate the research and development process. Most of the daily workflows would be centered around running batch jobs on EC2 instances with storage on EBS volumes. The CTO is concerned about meeting HIPAA compliance norms for sensitive data stored on EBS. Which of the following options outline the correct capabilities of an encrypted EBS volume? (Select three)",
        "choice1": "Data moving between the volume and the instance is encrypted",
        "choice2": "Data moving between the volume and the instance is NOT encrypted",
        "choice3": "Any snapshot created from the volume is NOT encrypted",
        "choice4": "Data at rest inside the volume is encrypted",
        "choice5": "Data at rest inside the volume is NOT encrypted",
        "choice6": "Any snapshot created from the volume is encrypted",
        "answer": "1,4,6",
        "multi": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "While troubleshooting, a cloud architect realized that the Amazon EC2 instance is unable to connect to the internet using the Internet Gateway. Which conditions should be met for internet connectivity to be established? (Select two)",
        "choice1": "The instance's subnet is associated with multiple route tables with conflicting configurations",
        "choice2": "The instance's subnet is not associated with any route table",
        "choice3": "The network ACLs associated with the subnet must have rules to allow inbound and outbound traffic",
        "choice4": "The route table in the instance’s subnet should have a route to an Internet Gateway",
        "choice5": "The subnet has been configured to be public and has no access to internet",
        "answer": "2,4",
        "multi": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A company's cloud architect has set up a solution that uses Route 53 to configure the DNS records for the primary website with the domain pointing to the Application Load Balancer (ALB). The company wants a solution where users will be directed to a static error page, configured as a backup, in case of unavailability of the primary website. Which configuration will meet the company's requirements, while keeping the changes to a bare minimum?",
        "choice1": "Set up a Route 53 active-active failover configuration. If Route 53 health check determines the ALB endpoint as unhealthy, the traffic will be diverted to a static error page, hosted on Amazon S3 bucket",
        "choice2": "Use Route 53 Latency-based routing. Create a latency record to point to the Amazon S3 bucket that holds the error page to be displayed",
        "choice3": "Use Route 53 Weighted routing to give minimum weight to Amazon S3 bucket that holds the error page to be displayed. In case of primary failure, the requests get routed to the error page",
        "choice4": "Set up a Route 53 active-passive failover configuration. If Route 53 health check determines the ALB endpoint as unhealthy, the traffic will be diverted to a static error page, hosted on Amazon S3 bucket",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Your firm has implemented a multi-tiered networking structure within the VPC - with two public and two private subnets. The public subnets are used to deploy the Application Load Balancers, while the two private subnets are used to deploy the application on Amazon EC2 instances. The development team wants the EC2 instances to have access to the internet. The solution has to be fully managed by AWS and needs to work over IPv4. What will you recommend?",
        "choice1": "NAT Instances deployed in your public subnet",
        "choice2": "Internet Gateways deployed in your private subnet",
        "choice3": "Egress-Only Internet Gateways deployed in your private subnet",
        "choice4": "NAT Gateways deployed in your public subnet",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An online gaming company wants to block access to its application from specific countries; however, the company wants to allow its remote development team (from one of the blocked countries) to have access to the application. The application is deployed on EC2 instances running under an Application Load Balancer (ALB) with AWS WAF. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions can be combined to address the given use-case? (Select two)",
        "choice1": "Use ALB geo match statement listing the countries that you want to block",
        "choice2": "Use WAF geo match statement listing the countries that you want to block",
        "choice3": "Use WAF IP set statement that specifies the IP addresses that you want to allow through",
        "choice4": "Create a deny rule for the blocked countries in the NACL associated to each of the EC2 instances",
        "choice5": "Use ALB IP set statement that specifies the IP addresses that you want to allow through",
        "answer": "2,3",
        "multi": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A company needs a massive PostgreSQL database and the engineering team would like to retain control over managing the patches, version upgrades for the database, and consistent performance with high IOPS. The team wants to install the database on an EC2 instance with the optimal storage type on the attached EBS volume. As a solutions architect, which of the following configurations would you suggest to the engineering team?",
        "choice1": "Amazon EC2 with EBS volume of General Purpose SSD (gp2) type",
        "choice2": "Amazon EC2 with EBS volume of Throughput Optimized HDD (st1) type",
        "choice3": "Amazon EC2 with EBS volume of Provisioned IOPS SSD (io1) type",
        "choice4": "Amazon EC2 with EBS volume of cold HDD (sc1) type",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company is looking for a technology that allows its mobile app users to connect through a Google login and have the capability to turn on MFA (Multi-Factor Authentication) to have maximum security. Ideally, the solution should be fully managed by AWS. Which technology do you recommend for managing the users' accounts?",
        "choice1": "Amazon Cognito",
        "choice2": "Write a Lambda function with Auth0 3rd party integration",
        "choice3": "AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)",
        "choice4": "Enable the AWS Google Login Service",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A pharma company is working on developing a vaccine for the COVID-19 virus. The researchers at the company want to process the reference healthcare data in an in-memory database that is highly available as well as HIPAA compliant. As a solutions architect, which of the following AWS services would you recommend for this task?",
        "choice1": "ElastiCache for Redis",
        "choice2": "DynamoDB",
        "choice3": "DocumentDB",
        "choice4": "ElastiCache for Memcached",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A leading media company wants to do an accelerated online migration of hundreds of terabytes of files from their on-premises data center to Amazon S3 and then establish a mechanism to access the migrated data for ongoing updates from the on-premises applications. As a solutions architect, which of the following would you select as the MOST performant solution for the given use-case?",
        "choice1": "Use File Gateway configuration of AWS Storage Gateway to migrate data to Amazon S3 and then use S3 Transfer Acceleration for ongoing updates from the on-premises applications",
        "choice2": "Use AWS DataSync to migrate existing data to Amazon S3 as well as access the S3 data for ongoing updates",
        "choice3": "Use AWS DataSync to migrate existing data to Amazon S3 and then use File Gateway to retain access to the migrated data for ongoing updates from the on-premises applications",
        "choice4": "Use S3 Transfer Acceleration to migrate existing data to Amazon S3 and then use DataSync for ongoing updates from the on-premises applications",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The engineering team at an online fashion retailer uses AWS Cloud to manage its technology infrastructure. The EC2 server fleet is behind an Application Load Balancer and the fleet strength is managed by an Auto Scaling group. Based on the historical data, the team is anticipating a huge traffic spike during the upcoming Thanksgiving sale. As an AWS solutions architect, what feature of the Auto Scaling group would you leverage so that the potential surge in traffic can be preemptively addressed?",
        "choice1": "Auto Scaling group target tracking scaling policy",
        "choice2": "Auto Scaling group step scaling policy",
        "choice3": "Auto Scaling group lifecycle hook",
        "choice4": "Auto Scaling group scheduled action",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An Internet-of-Things (IoT) company is looking for a database solution on AWS Cloud that has Auto Scaling capabilities and is highly available. The database should be able to handle any changes in data attributes over time, in case the company updates the data feed from its IoT devices. The database must provide the capability to output a continuous stream with details of any changes to the underlying data. As a Solutions Architect, which database will you recommend?",
        "choice1": "Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS)",
        "choice2": "Amazon DynamoDB",
        "choice3": "Amazon Aurora",
        "choice4": "Amazon Redshift",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An application hosted on Amazon EC2 contains sensitive personal information about all its customers and needs to be protected from all types of cyber-attacks. The company is considering using the AWS Web Application Firewall (WAF) to handle this requirement. Can you identify the correct solution leveraging the capabilities of WAF?",
        "choice1": "Create a CloudFront distribution for the application on Amazon EC2 instances. Deploy AWS WAF on Amazon CloudFront to provide the necessary safety measures",
        "choice2": "Configure an Application Load Balancer (ALB) to balance the workload for all the EC2 instances. Configure CloudFront to distribute from an ALB since WAF cannot be directly configured on ALBs. This configuration not only provides necessary safety but is scalable too",
        "choice3": "AWS WAF can be directly configured on Amazon EC2 instances for ensuring the security of the underlying application data*",
        "choice4": "AWS WAF can be directly configured only on an Application Load Balancer (ALB) or an Amazon API Gateway. One of these two services can then be configured with Amazon EC2 to build the needed secure architecture",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company wants to publish an event into an SQS queue whenever a new object is uploaded on S3. Which of the following statements are true regarding this functionality?",
        "choice1": "Both Standard SQS queue and FIFO SQS queue are allowed as an Amazon S3 event notification destination",
        "choice2": "Neither Standard SQS queue nor FIFO SQS queue is allowed as an Amazon S3 event notification destination",
        "choice3": "Only FIFO SQS queue is allowed as an Amazon S3 event notification destination, whereas Standard SQS queue is not allowed",
        "choice4": "Only Standard SQS queue is allowed as an Amazon S3 event notification destination, whereas FIFO SQS queue is not allowed",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A medical devices company uses S3 buckets to store critical data. Hundreds of buckets are used to keep the data segregated and well organized. Recently, the development team noticed that the lifecycle policies on the S3 buckets have not been applied optimally, resulting in higher costs. As a Solutions Architect, can you recommend a solution to reduce storage costs on S3 while keeping the IT team's involvement to a minimum?",
        "choice1": "Configure Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS) to provide a fast, cost-effective and sharable storage service",
        "choice2": "Use S3 One Zone-Infrequent Access, to reduce the costs on S3 storage",
        "choice3": "Use S3 Intelligent-Tiering storage class to optimize the S3 storage costs",
        "choice4": "Use S3 Outposts storage class to reduce the costs on S3 storage by storing the data on-premises",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A leading video streaming provider is migrating to AWS Cloud infrastructure for delivering its content to users across the world. The company wants to make sure that the solution supports at least a million requests per second for its EC2 server farm. As a solutions architect, which type of Elastic Load Balancer would you recommend as part of the solution stack?",
        "choice1": "Network Load Balancer",
        "choice2": "Application Load Balancer",
        "choice3": "Classic Load Balancer",
        "choice4": "Infrastructure Load Balancer",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A silicon valley based healthcare startup uses AWS Cloud for its IT infrastructure. The startup stores patient health records on Amazon S3. The engineering team needs to implement an archival solution based on Amazon S3 Glacier to enforce regulatory and compliance controls on data access. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions would you recommend?",
        "choice1": "Use S3 Glacier to store the sensitive archived data and then use an S3 lifecycle policy to enforce compliance controls",
        "choice2": "Use S3 Glacier vault to store the sensitive archived data and then use an S3 Access Control List to enforce compliance controls",
        "choice3": "Use S3 Glacier to store the sensitive archived data and then use an S3 Access Control List to enforce compliance controls",
        "choice4": "Use S3 Glacier vault to store the sensitive archived data and then use a vault lock policy to enforce compliance controls",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An application with global users across AWS Regions had suffered an issue when the Elastic Load Balancer (ELB) in a Region malfunctioned thereby taking down the traffic with it. The manual intervention cost the company significant time and resulted in major revenue loss. What should a solutions architect recommend to reduce internet latency and add automatic failover across AWS Regions?",
        "choice1": "Set up AWS Direct Connect as the backbone for each of the AWS Regions where the application is deployed",
        "choice2": "Create S3 buckets in different AWS Regions and configure CloudFront to pick the nearest edge location to the user",
        "choice3": "Set up AWS Global Accelerator and add endpoints to cater to users in different geographic locations",
        "choice4": "Set up an Amazon Route 53 geoproximity routing policy to route traffic*",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A financial services firm uses a high-frequency trading system and wants to write the log files into Amazon S3. The system will also read these log files in parallel on a near real-time basis. The engineering team wants to address any data discrepancies that might arise when the trading system overwrites an existing log file and then tries to read that specific log file. Which of the following options BEST describes the capabilities of Amazon S3 relevant to this scenario?",
        "choice1": "A process replaces an existing object and immediately tries to read it. Until the change is fully propagated, Amazon S3 might return the previous data",
        "choice2": "A process replaces an existing object and immediately tries to read it. Until the change is fully propagated, Amazon S3 does not return any data",
        "choice3": "A process replaces an existing object and immediately tries to read it. Amazon S3 always returns the latest version of the object",
        "choice4": "A process replaces an existing object and immediately tries to read it. Until the change is fully propagated, Amazon S3 might return the new data",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An e-commerce company uses Amazon SQS queues to decouple their application architecture. The engineering team has observed message processing failures for some customer orders. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions would you recommend for handling such message failures?",
        "choice1": "Use a temporary queue to handle message processing failures",
        "choice2": "Use a dead-letter queue to handle message processing failures",
        "choice3": "Use short polling to handle message processing failures",
        "choice4": "Use long polling to handle message processing failures",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A development team has deployed a microservice to the ECS. The application layer is in a Docker container that provides both static and dynamic content through an Application Load Balancer. With increasing load, the ECS cluster is experiencing higher network usage. The development team has looked into the network usage and found that 90% of it is due to distributing static content of the application. As a Solutions Architect, what do you recommend to improve the application's network usage and decrease costs?",
        "choice1": "Distribute the dynamic content through Amazon S3",
        "choice2": "Distribute the static content through Amazon EFS",
        "choice3": "Distribute the static content through Amazon S3",
        "choice4": "Distribute the dynamic content through Amazon EFS",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A startup has created a cost-effective backup solution in another AWS Region. The application is running in warm standby mode and has Application Load Balancer (ALB) to support it from the front. The current failover process is manual and requires updating the DNS alias record to point to the secondary ALB in another Region in case of failure of the primary ALB. As a Solutions Architect, what will you recommend to automate the failover process?",
        "choice1": "Enable an ALB health check",
        "choice2": "Enable an EC2 instance health check",
        "choice3": "Configure Trusted Advisor to check on unhealthy instances",
        "choice4": "Enable an Amazon Route 53 health check",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A social media analytics company uses a fleet of EC2 servers to manage its analytics workflow. These EC2 servers operate under an Auto Scaling group. The engineers at the company want to be able to download log files whenever an instance terminates because of a scale-in event from an auto-scaling policy. Which of the following features can be used to enable this custom action?",
        "choice1": "EC2 instance meta data",
        "choice2": "EC2 instance user data",
        "choice3": "Auto Scaling group scheduled action",
        "choice4": "Auto Scaling group lifecycle hook",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An Internet-of-Things (IoT) company is planning on distributing a master sensor in people's homes to measure the key metrics from its smart devices. In order to provide adjustment commands for these devices, the company would like to have a streaming system that supports ordered data based on the sensor's key, and also sustains high throughput messages (thousands of messages per second). As a solutions architect, which of the following AWS services would you recommend for this use-case?",
        "choice1": "Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS)",
        "choice2": "Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS)",
        "choice3": "Amazon Kinesis Data Streams (KDS)",
        "choice4": "AWS Lambda",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An IT company has built a custom data warehousing solution for a retail organization by using Amazon Redshift. As part of the cost optimizations, the company wants to move any historical data (any data older than a year) into S3, as the daily analytical reports consume data for just the last one year. However the analysts want to retain the ability to cross-reference this historical data along with the daily reports. The company wants to develop a solution with the LEAST amount of effort and MINIMUM cost. As a solutions architect, which option would you recommend to facilitate this use-case?",
        "choice1": "Setup access to the historical data via Athena. The analytics team can run historical data queries on Athena and continue the daily reporting on Redshift. In case the reports need to be cross-referenced, the analytics team need to export these in flat files and then do further analysis",
        "choice2": "Use the Redshift COPY command to load the S3 based historical data into Redshift. Once the ad-hoc queries are run for the historic data, it can be removed from Redshift",
        "choice3": "Use Redshift Spectrum to create Redshift cluster tables pointing to the underlying historical data in S3. The analytics team can then query this historical data to cross-reference with the daily reports from Redshift",
        "choice4": "Use Glue ETL job to load the S3 based historical data into Redshift. Once the ad-hoc queries are run for the historic data, it can be removed from Redshift",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company wants to ensure high availability for its RDS database. The development team wants to opt for Multi-AZ deployment and they would like to understand what happens when the primary instance of the Multi-AZ configuration goes down. As a Solutions Architect, which of the following will you identify as the outcome of the scenario?",
        "choice1": "The CNAME record will be updated to point to the standby DB",
        "choice2": "The URL to access the database will change to the standby DB",
        "choice3": "An email will be sent to the System Administrator asking for manual intervention",
        "choice4": "The application will be down until the primary database has recovered itself",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A silicon valley based startup helps its users legally sign highly confidential contracts. To meet the compliance guidelines, the startup must ensure that the signed contracts are encrypted using the AES-256 algorithm via an encryption key that is generated internally. The startup is now migrating to AWS Cloud and would like you to advise them on the encryption scheme to adopt. The startup wants to continue using their existing encryption key generation mechanism. What do you recommend?",
        "choice1": "SSE-KMS",
        "choice2": "SSE-S3",
        "choice3": "SSE-C",
        "choice4": "Client-Side Encryption",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A retail company wants to establish encrypted network connectivity between its on-premises data center and AWS Cloud. The company wants to get the solution up and running in the fastest possible time and it should also support encryption in transit. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions would you suggest to the company?",
        "choice1": "Use Site-to-Site VPN to establish encrypted network connectivity between the on-premises data center and AWS Cloud",
        "choice2": "Use AWS Direct Connect to establish encrypted network connectivity between the on-premises data center and AWS Cloud",
        "choice3": "Use AWS Data Sync to establish encrypted network connectivity between the on-premises data center and AWS Cloud",
        "choice4": "Use AWS Secrets Manager to establish encrypted network connectivity between the on-premises data center and AWS Cloud",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company has noticed that its application performance has deteriorated after a new Auto Scaling group was deployed a few days back. Upon investigation, the team found out that the Launch Configuration selected for the Auto Scaling group is using the incorrect instance type that is not optimized to handle the application workflow. As a solutions architect, what would you recommend to provide a long term resolution for this issue?",
        "choice1": "Modify the launch configuration to use the correct instance type and continue to use the existing Auto Scaling group",
        "choice2": "No need to modify the launch configuration. Just modify the Auto Scaling group to use the correct instance type",
        "choice3": "No need to modify the launch configuration. Just modify the Auto Scaling group to use more number of existing instance types. More instances may offset the loss of performance",
        "choice4": "Create a new launch configuration to use the correct instance type. Modify the Auto Scaling group to use this new launch configuration. Delete the old launch configuration as it is no longer needed",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A financial services company has to retain the activity logs for each of their customers to meet compliance guidelines. Depending on the business line, the company wants to retain the logs for 5-10 years in highly available and durable storage on AWS. The overall data size is expected to be in PetaBytes. In case of an audit, the data would need to be accessible within a timeframe of up to 48 hours. Which AWS storage option is the MOST cost-effective for the given compliance requirements?",
        "choice1": "Amazon S3 Glacier",
        "choice2": "Third-party tape storage",
        "choice3": "Amazon S3 Glacier Deep Archive",
        "choice4": "Amazon S3 Standard storage",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A health-care company manages its web application on Amazon EC2 instances running behind Auto Scaling group (ASG). The company provides ambulances for critical patients and needs the application to be reliable. The workload of the company can be managed on 2 EC2 instances and can peak up to 6 instances when traffic increases. As a Solutions Architect, which of the following configurations would you select as the best fit for these requirements?",
        "choice1": "The ASG should be configured with the minimum capacity set to 2, with 1 instance each in two different Availability Zones. The maximum capacity of the ASG should be set to 6",
        "choice2": "The ASG should be configured with the minimum capacity set to 4, with 2 instances each in two different Availability Zones. The maximum capacity of the ASG should be set to 6",
        "choice3": "The ASG should be configured with the minimum capacity set to 2 and the maximum capacity set to 6 in a single Availability Zone",
        "choice4": "The ASG should be configured with the minimum capacity set to 4, with 2 instances each in two different AWS Regions. The maximum capacity of the ASG should be set to 6",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true regarding cross-zone load balancing as seen in Application Load  Balancer versus Network Load Balancer?",
        "choice1": "By default, cross-zone load balancing is disabled for both Application Load Balancer and Network Load Balancer",
        "choice2": "By default, cross-zone load balancing is enabled for both Application Load Balancer and Network Load Balancer",
        "choice3": "By default, cross-zone load balancing is enabled for Application Load Balancer and disabled for Network Load Balancer",
        "choice4": "By default, cross-zone load balancing is disabled for Application Load Balancer and enabled for Network Load Balancer",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A DevOps engineer at an IT company was recently added to the admin group of the company's AWS account. The AdministratorAccess managed policy is attached to this group. Can you identify the AWS tasks that the DevOps engineer CANNOT perform even though he has full Administrator privileges (Select two)?",
        "choice1": "Delete the IAM user for his manager",
        "choice2": "Configure an Amazon S3 bucket to enable MFA (Multi Factor Authentication) delete",
        "choice3": "Delete an S3 bucket from the production environment",
        "choice4": "Change the password for his own IAM user account",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A cyber security company is running a mission critical application using a single Spread placement group of EC2 instances. The company needs 15 Amazon EC2 instances for optimal performance. How many Availability Zones (AZs) will the company need to deploy these EC2 instances per the given use-case?",
        "choice1": "7",
        "choice2": "14",
        "choice3": "15",
        "choice4": "3",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Your company is evolving towards a microservice approach for their website. The company plans to expose the website from the same load balancer, linked to different target groups with different URLs, that are similar to these - checkout.mycorp.com, www.mycorp.com, mycorp.com/profile, and mycorp.com/search. As a Solutions Architect, which Load Balancer type do you recommend to achieve this routing feature with MINIMUM configuration and development effort?",
        "choice1": "Create an NGINX based load balancer on an EC2 instance to have advanced routing capabilities",
        "choice2": "Create a Network Load Balancer",
        "choice3": "Create an Application Load Balancer",
        "choice4": "Create a Classic Load Balancer",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A financial services company is moving its IT infrastructure to AWS Cloud and wants to enforce adequate data protection mechanisms on Amazon S3 to meet compliance guidelines. The engineering team has hired you as a solutions architect to build a solution for this requirement. Can you help the team identify the INCORRECT option from the choices below?",
        "choice1": "S3 can protect data at rest using Server-Side Encryption",
        "choice2": "S3 can protect data at rest using Client-Side Encryption",
        "choice3": "S3 can encrypt object metadata by using Server-Side Encryption",
        "choice4": "S3 can encrypt data in transit using HTTPS (TLS)",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "An automobile company is running its flagship application on a fleet of EC2 instances behind an Auto Scaling Group (ASG). The ASG has been configured more than a year ago. A young developer has just joined the development team and wants to understand the best practices to manage and configure an ASG. As a Solutions Architect, which of these would you identify as the key characteristics that the developer needs to understand regarding ASG configurations? (Select three)",
        "choice1": "EC2 Auto Scaling groups can span Availability Zones, but not AWS regions",
        "choice2": "If you configure the ASG to a certain base capacity, you cannot use a combined purchasing model to fulfill the instance requirements. You will need to choose either On-Demand instances or Reserved Instances only",
        "choice3": "Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling can automatically add a volume when the existing one is approaching capacity. This, however, is a configuration parameter and needs to be set explicitly",
        "choice4": "You can only specify one launch configuration for an EC2 Auto Scaling group at a time. But, you can modify a launch configuration after you've created it",
        "choice5": "If you have an EC2 Auto Scaling group (ASG) with running instances and you choose to delete the ASG, the instances will be terminated and the ASG will be deleted",
        "choice6": "Data is not automatically copied from existing instances to a new dynamically created instance",
        "answer": "1,5,6",
        "multi": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "A media company wants to get out of the business of owning and maintaining its own IT infrastructure. As part of this digital transformation, the media company wants to archive about 5PB of data in its on-premises data center to durable long term storage. As a solutions architect, what is your recommendation to migrate this data in the MOST cost-optimal way?",
        "choice1": "Transfer the on-premises data into multiple Snowball Edge Storage Optimized devices. Copy the Snowball Edge data into AWS Glacier",
        "choice2": "Setup AWS direct connect between the on-premises data center and AWS Cloud. Use this connection to transfer the data into AWS Glacier",
        "choice3": "Setup Site-to-Site VPN connection between the on-premises data center and AWS Cloud. Use this connection to transfer the data into AWS Glacier",
        "choice4": "Transfer the on-premises data into multiple Snowball Edge Storage Optimized devices. Copy the Snowball Edge data into Amazon S3 and create a lifecycle policy to transition the data into AWS Glacier",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The engineering team at a weather tracking company wants to enhance the performance of its relation database and is looking for a caching solution that supports geospatial data. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions will you suggest?",
        "choice1": "Use Amazon ElastiCache for Memcached",
        "choice2": "Amazon DynamoDB Accelerator (DAX)",
        "choice3": "AWS Global Accelerator",
        "choice4": "Use Amazon ElastiCache for Redis",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A streaming solutions company is building a video streaming product by using an Application Load Balancer (ALB) that routes the requests to the underlying EC2 instances. The engineering team has noticed a peculiar pattern. The ALB removes an instance whenever it is detected as unhealthy but the Auto Scaling group fails to kick-in and provision the replacement instance. What could explain this anomaly?",
        "choice1": "The Auto Scaling group is using ALB based health check and the Application Load Balancer is using EC2 based health check",
        "choice2": "The Auto Scaling group is using EC2 based health check and the Application Load Balancer is using ALB based health check",
        "choice3": "Both the Auto Scaling group and Application Load Balancer are using ALB based health check",
        "choice4": "Both the Auto Scaling group and Application Load Balancer are using EC2 based health check",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You have just terminated an instance in the us-west-1a availability zone. The attached EBS volume is now available for attachment to other instances. An intern launches a new Linux EC2 instance in the us-west-1b availability zone and is attempting to attach the EBS volume. The intern informs you that it is not possible and needs your help. Which of the following explanations would you provide to them?",
        "choice1": "EBS volumes are AZ locked",
        "choice2": "EBS volumes are region locked",
        "choice3": "The required IAM permissions are missing",
        "choice4": "The EBS volume is encrypted",
        "answer": 1,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A company runs its EC2 servers behind an Application Load Balancer along with an Auto Scaling group. The engineers at the company want to be able to install proprietary tools on each instance and perform a pre-activation status check of these tools whenever an instance is provisioned because of a scale-out event from an auto-scaling policy. Which of the following options can be used to enable this custom action?",
        "choice1": "Use the Auto Scaling group scheduled action to put the instance in a wait state and launch a custom script that installs the proprietary forensic tools and performs a pre-activation status check",
        "choice2": "Use the EC2 instance meta data to put the instance in a wait state and launch a custom script that installs the proprietary forensic tools and performs a pre-activation status check",
        "choice3": "Use the EC2 instance user data to put the instance in a wait state and launch a custom script that installs the proprietary forensic tools and performs a pre-activation status check",
        "choice4": "Use the Auto Scaling group lifecycle hook to put the instance in a wait state and launch a custom script that installs the proprietary forensic tools and performs a pre-activation status check",
        "answer": 4,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A DevOps engineer at an organization is debugging issues related to an Amazon EC2 instance. The engineer has SSH'ed into the instance and he needs to retrieve the instance public IP from within a shell script running on the instance command line. Can you identify the correct URL path to get the instance public IP?",
        "choice1": "http://169.254.169.254/latest/user-data/public-ipv4",
        "choice2": "http://254.169.254.169/latest/meta-data/public-ipv4",
        "choice3": "http://169.254.169.254/latest/meta-data/public-ipv4",
        "choice4": "http://254.169.254.169/latest/user-data/public-ipv4",
        "answer": 3,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "You have built an application that is deployed with an Elastic Load Balancer and an Auto Scaling Group. As a Solutions Architect, you have configured aggressive CloudWatch alarms, making your Auto Scaling Group (ASG) scale in and out very quickly, renewing your fleet of Amazon EC2 instances on a daily basis. A production bug appeared two days ago, but the team is unable to SSH into the instance to debug the issue, because the instance has already been terminated by the ASG. The log files are saved on the EC2 instance. How will you resolve the issue and make sure it doesn't happen again?",
        "choice1": "Disable the Termination from the ASG any time a user reports an issue",
        "choice2": "Make a snapshot of the EC2 instance just before it gets terminated",
        "choice3": "Install a CloudWatch Logs agents on the EC2 instances to send logs to CloudWatch",
        "choice4": "Use AWS Lambda to regularly SSH into the EC2 instances and copy the log files to S3",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A mobile chat application uses DynamoDB as its database service to provide low latency chat updates. A new developer has joined the team and is reviewing the configuration settings for DynamoDB which have been tweaked for certain technical requirements. CloudTrail service has been enabled on all the resources used for the project. Yet, DynamoDB encryption details are nowhere to be found. Which of the following options can explain the root cause for the given issue?",
        "choice1": "By default, all DynamoDB tables are encrypted under AWS managed CMKs, which do not write to CloudTrail logs",
        "choice2": "By default, all DynamoDB tables are encrypted under an AWS owned customer master key (CMK), which do not write to CloudTrail logs",
        "choice3": "By default, all DynamoDB tables are encrypted under Customer managed CMKs, which do not write to CloudTrail logs",
        "choice4": "By default, all DynamoDB tables are encrypted using Data keys, which do not write to CloudTrail logs",
        "answer": 2,
        "multi": 0
    }
]